Harsh Pandey

4 years of Adtech and e-commerce analytics, driving value and scale and growth. Expertise in ETL, Data Mining, Analytics, Reporting, turning Rest APIs to data pipelines, reporting and leading technical conversations, statistical analysis predicting and exploratory, regression, time series forecasting, classification.

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/harshvp

Cell: +1 (317) 793 8959

Email: harshvardhanpandey@hotmail.com

Github: github.com/geekidharsh

Stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/story/5893695

Skills

Proficient: Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Pandas, Bash scripting, Google Cloud Platform, Big Query.

Databases: Relational and NoSQL, MySQL, Google BigQuery, Postgres DB, PySpark (familiar)...

Analytics Tools: Adwords, Google Analytics, Webmasters, Brightedge, Ahref.

Certifications

Certified Data Engineering on Google Cloud - Google Cloud Google Analytics Certified - Google Analytics Data Scientist Nanodegree, Udacity.

Experience

Data Engineer - Analytics

Dec 2017 - Present

MilliporeSigma (Merck KGaA), Saint Louis, MO

Search Query Revenue Model - Designed a Search Query Revenue Model to analyzes and predict revenue from search queries. Wrote API interfaces from 5 sources. Ingest, transform and store over 50TB of data into reports. Defined revenue attribution algorithm to generate metrics based on individual as well as the multi-touch customer journey.

Utilized Python, Google Big Query, pandas and Google Data Studio for reporting.

Advanced Keyword Research Database - Developed a data warehouse all the way to reporting that consolidates dataset from various internal & external systems bring billions of data points and automate keyword recommendations. Results: 30% revenue from ad optimization, higher conversions, \$100 million on \$12.6 million budget. Utilized Google Big Query for warehouse, cluster on google cloud pandas and pySpark for processing, SQL, Power Bi and Data Studio for Reporting.

Content generation using Machine learning - Build a n-sentences META tags generator for over 120k html product pages using Summarizer neural-network APIs in python. Employed ML random forest classifier to test results, verified the quality with the Content Team. Supervisor to Summer Data Science interns.

Results: Exponential growth in traffic to pages that were unidentified, now over 70% of them ranking Above the Fold on SERP.

Project Migration to Bitbucket - Migrated existing projects and new project from across organizations and consolidated them to one central repository on bitbucket. Results: Improved SDLC across developers from different division, faster feature improvement & better maintenance.

Analyst - E-Commerce

MilliporeSigma (Merck KGaA), Burlington, MA

April 2016 - Dec 2017

Overall estimated revenue growth in Paid and SEO from some of the projects combined is over 33% globally.

Search Console App - A cli/terminal based app for client, written in python that used Webmaster's Search Console API to simplify the entire data flow from Google servers to your local client machine.

Techstack and more about SearchConsoleApp: python (core), py modules: http, oauth2, sys, argv, pandas, os. Shell, database local instance: MySQL, Big Query

HTTP to HTTPS Migration - Collaborated with CRM, Product managers to build analyzed models and data pipelines to measure possible impact of migrating a large e-commerce website from successful http/https migration with minimal negative impact on organic traffic. Monitored the impact month over month as a final report on Google Data Studio. Results: The site still brandished a 1% increase in organic, impressive for a large website.

Other Projects - Automated Organic Keyword Database, Scalable Reporting System using Big Query and Data Studio

Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science

University of Illinois, Springfield, IL

Feb 2015 to Dec 2015

• Researcher on medical and traffic projects. Utilized SQL with bash automation scripts to manage database, perform complex analysis and dynamic reporting. Designed ER models and database for the management, data mining and analytics

Notable Projects:

Utilizing annotated medical records and DMV datasets to understand driving pattern and common casualties and conclude recommendations to improve. Built staging of multivariate sources of drivers database from all around IL's DMV. Used feedback to lead statewide social media campaigns on roadside safety awareness and improving safe driving.

Backend Web Engineer

Fine Brains Consulting, Raipur, India

June 2013 - Jul 2014

Network Systems Intern,

Institute of Management Technology, Delhi

India

Summer 2011, Ghaziabad, India

Education

 $\textbf{MS, Computer Science.} \ University \ of \ Illinois \ at \ Spring field, \ IL. \ May \ 2016$

BE, Computer Science. CSVTU, Bhilai, India. June 2013

Publications

"Present Scenario Analysis Of Green Computing Approach In The World Of Information Technology", Undergraduate Academic Research Journal (UARJ), ISSN: 2278 1129, Volume-1, Issue-2, H. Pandey.

Leadership

Meetup Organizer.

Grew a brand new meetup to now one of Boston Area's Largest cultural meetup.

Chicago Tech Ideas. Award winning finalist team at the Chicago Ideas Week in 2015.